A Guide to the Evans Family Papers 1709-1928
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Evans Family Papers, 1709-1928
Library of Virginia
39664
10.75 cubic feet and 1 volume
Evans Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of J. Wayne Adams, Jr., South Boston, 20 June 2002.
Biographical Information
The Evans family were prominent residents of Paoli, Chester County, Pennsylvania, and South Boston, Virginia. Joshua Evans, Jr. was born in Paoli on 20 January 1777. He was a hotel keeper and farmer, and served one term in the Pennsylvania House of Representatives (1820) and two terms in the United States House of Representatives (1829-1833). He married Lydia Davis. She was the daughter of Dr. John Davis (1744- 1816), and was born on 2 February 1778. She died shortly after the birth of their fifth child, on 20 November 1818. Joshua Evans, Jr. died in Paoli on 2 October 1846 and is buried in the Great Valley Baptist Church cemetery in New Centerville, Pennsylvania.
His son John D. Evans was born on 18 October 1814. He lived his entire life in Paoli, and took over the hotel business after his father died. He was also a farmer, and a partner in the Columbia Manufacturing Company. He owned rental property in Philadelphia as well. John D. Evans never married. He died at his home in Paoli on 6 June 1884.
His "adopted son" was Edward Livingston Evans. Born Edward Livingston on 2 January 1857, he was orphaned at a young age and resided in an orphanage in Philadelphia under the charge of John D. Evans' cousin Nathaniel Jones. Evans later assumed much of the expense for his care. Edward Livingston took the last name Evans around 1873. He later resided in Farmville, Virginia in the residence of Major Andrew R. Venable, Jr., and graduated from Hampden-Sidney College. He married Mildred Blanton on 22 April 1884. They had ten children and resided in South Boston, Virginia where he was employed in the hardware business, as well as in the lumber business and in manufacturing of building material, and also in the tobacco business. He served as a town councilman and was mayor for two terms. He died at his home in South Boston on 15 March 1909.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1709-1928, of the Evans family of Paoli, Chester County, Pennsylvania and South Boston, Halifax County, Virginia. The majority of the collection relates to the activities of Joshua Evans, Jr. (1777- 1846), John Davis Evans (1814-1884), and Edward Livingston Evans (1857-1909). Includes correspondence, accounts and receipts, estate papers, subject files, oversized items, framed items, and a ledger containing miscellaneous papers.
Organization
Organized into the following seven series: I. Correspondence.
II. Accounts and Receipts.
III. Estate Papers.
IV. Subject Files.
V. Oversized Items.
VI. Framed Items.
VII. Ledger.
The microfilm is organized in the following manner:
Misc. Reel 4172: Box 1 Folder 1 - Box 3 Folder 8
Misc. Reel 4173: Box 3 Folder 9 - Box 6 Folder 3
Misc. Reel 4174: Box 6 Folder 4 - Box 7 Folder 19
Misc. Reel 4175: Box 7 Folder 20 - Box 9 Folder 18
Misc. Reel 4176: Box 10 Folders 1-54
Misc. Reel 4177: Box 10 Folder 55 - Box 11 Folder 9
Misc. Reel 4178: Box 11 Folders 10-19
Misc. Reel 4179: Box 11 Folders 20-32
Misc. Reel 4180: Box 12 Folders 1-17
Misc. Reel 4181: Box 13 Folders 1-14
Misc. Reel 4182: Box 13 Folder 15 - Box 14 Folder 7
Misc. Reel 4183: Box 15 Folders 1-25
Misc. Reel 4184: Box 15 Folder 26 - Box 16 Folder 29
Misc. Reel 4185: Box 17 Folders 1 - Box 18 Folder 7
Misc. Reel 4186: Box 18 Folders 8-15
Misc. Reel 4187: Box 18 Folder 16 - Box 19 Folder 4
Misc. Reel 4188: Box 19 Folder 5 - Box 20 Folder 1
Misc. Reel 4189: Box 20 Folder 2 - Box 21 Folder 10
Misc. Reel 4190: Box 21 Folder 11
Misc. Reel 4191: Box 22 Folder 1- Box 24 Folder 15
Misc. Reel 4192: Boxes 25-26
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence (Box Box 1-9)
  The correspondence begins in 1770, but the majority is post-1810. Most of the letters between 1810 and 1840 are addressed to Joshua Evans, Jr. and his sister-in-law Sarah Davis (1784-1857), who moved in with the family following the death of his wife, Lydia Evans, in 1818. There is a good deal of correspondence written to Davis from her sisters in Havre de Grace, Maryland. Also of note are letters written to Joshua Evans, Jr. while he was serving in the Pennsylvania House of Representatives (1820) and the United States House of Representatives (1829-1833). Subjects include state and national political issues, the introduction of various petitions to the legislature, political patronage and appointments, taxation issues, the annexation of Texas, removal of deposits from the Bank of the United States, letters regarding pensions and bounty land of Revolutionary War veterans, party politics, tariff matters, and internal improvements.
  The correspondence between 1840 and 1880 is mostly to John D. Evans, as well as Sarah Davis. There are a number of letters from his sister Mary M. Baily while she was living in Memphis, Cincinnati, and Troy, New York. She describes her medical studies while attending the Troy Female Seminary. Many of the letters contain her views on women's rights, and also relate to her separation and divorce from her husband John P. Baily (b. 1805). There is a good deal of correspondence concerning the settlement of the estate of their father Joshua Evans. Also included are letters between John D. Evans and the Pennsylvania Railroad Company concerning damages to his property by the railroad.
  The correspondence after 1880 concerns the activities of Edward Livingston Evans of South Boston, Virginia. There are a large number of letters between him and his future wife Mildred Blanton of Farmville concerning their courtship and marriage. Much of the correspondence also relates to his activities in the hardware business, as well as legal and financial matters. Also included are letters of sympathy written to the family upon his death on 15 March 1909.
  Chrononlogical
  - 1770 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1783-1789 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1790-1796 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1803-1808 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1810 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1811 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1812 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1813 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1814 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1815 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1816 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1817 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1818 (January-June) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1818 (July-December) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1819 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1820 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1821 (January-February) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1821 (March-December) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1822 (January-June) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1822 (July-December) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1823 (January-June) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1823 (July-December) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1824 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1825 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1826 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1827 (January-July) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1827 (August-December) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1828 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1829 (January-November) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1829 (December) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1830 (January) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1830 (February) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1830 (March-May) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1830 (October, December) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1831 (January) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1831 (February-March) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1831 (August, November-December) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1832 (January-May) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1832 (June-December) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1833 (January-March) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1833 (April-December) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1834 (January-June) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1834 (July-December) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1835 (January-June) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1835 (July-December) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1836 (January-June) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1836 (July-December) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1837 (January-June) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1837 (July-December) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1838 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1839 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1840 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1841 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1842 (January-June) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1842 (July-December) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1843 (January-June) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1843 (July-December) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1844 (January-June) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1844 (July-December) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1845 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1846 (January-June) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1846 (July-December) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1847 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1848 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1849 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1850 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1851 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1852 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1853 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1854 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1855 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1856 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1857 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1858 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1859 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1860 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1861 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1862 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1863 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 1864 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1865 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 1866 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 1867 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 1868 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 1870 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 1871 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 1872 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 1873 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 1874 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 1877 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 1878 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 1879 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 1880 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1881 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1882 (June) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1882 (July 1-15) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1882 (July 16-31) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1883 (March-June) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1883 (August) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1883 (September) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1883 (October) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1883 (November) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1884 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1885 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1886 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1887 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 1888 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1889 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1890 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1891 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 1892 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 1893 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 1894 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 1895 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 1896 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 1897 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1898 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1899 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1900 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1901 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1903 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1904 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1905 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1906 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1907 (January, April) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1907 (May) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1907 (June) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1907 (August-December) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1908 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1909 (January-February) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1909 (March 1-15) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1909 (March 16-17) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 1909 (March 18-19) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - 1909 (March 20-31) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - 1909 (April-June) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - 1911-1912, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - 1928 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - n.d. - Baily, Mary Malin (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - n.d. - Davis, Ann Elizabeth (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - n.d. - Davis, Mary G. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - n.d. - Davis, Sarah (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - n.d. - Evans, Edward F. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - n.d. - Evans, Edward L. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - n.d. - Evans, John D. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - n.d. - Evans, Lydia (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - n.d. - Evans, Mildred (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - n.d. - Evans, Pattie (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - n.d. - Morgan, Mary (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - n.d. - Rulong, Sarah (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - n.d. - Wayne, Isaac (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - n.d. - Willing, Charles (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - n.d. - Willing, Rosalind (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - n.d. - Wiltse, Pattie S. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - n.d. - Misc. Individuals (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
- Series II. Acounts and Receipts (Box Box 10-11.)
  The accounts and receipts cover the years 1806 to 1909. Most of them relate to the operation of the Paoli Inn by Joshua Evans, Jr. and his son John D. Evans.
  Chronological by year.
  - 1806-1868 (Box 10, Folder 1-62)
  - 1869-1909, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1-32)
- Series III. Estate Papers (Box Box 12-14)
  The estate papers contain information on numerous individuals for whose estates Joshua Evans and John D. Evans served as executor or administrator. There is a large amount of material on the estates of John Campbell, Robert Clemens, Henry and Margaret Dermont, Frederick Landis, Philip Landis, and Nathaniel and Jane Lawrence. See the container list for a complete listing of individuals.
  Alphabetical by name of decedent.
  - Andrew, Caleb (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Baugh, Sarah (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Campbell, John (Box 12, Folder 3-7)
  - Clemens, Robert (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - Crow, Ann (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Davis, Dr. John (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Dermont, Henry and Margaret (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
  - Emlen, George Jr. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Evans, Joshua Jr. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Evans, Lydia (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Hampton, Harvey (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hampton, Joseph (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hampton, Thomas (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hughes, Mrs. Elizabeth (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hughes, Ephraim (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Landis, Frederick (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
  - Landis, Philip (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - Lawrence, Nathaniel and Jane (Box 13, Folder 11-15)
  - Low, James (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Parke, Robert (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Phillips, Abram (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Richison, Mary (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Rulong, Mary (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Rulong, Sarah (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Wayne, Dr. Charles (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Series IV. Subject Files (Box Box 15-21)
  The subject files include account books, agreements, accounts and correspondence with the brokerage firm Thomas A. Biddle and Company, cancelled checks, circulars, clippings, and information concerning the Columbia Manufacturing Company in which John D. Evans was a partner. There are also deeds, exercise books on geometry and oceanography, guardianship papers, invitations, travel journals, and memorandum books. There are a large number of bank statements for the firm Norwood & Company in Halifax County. Also included in the subject files is information on the Paoli Monument, powers of attorney, promissory notes, information on rental property owned by John D. Evans, report cards, resolutions, tavern licenses, tax tickets and receipts, and other items.
  Alphabetical.
  - Account Book - Planters and Merchants Bank (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Account Book - Various Estates (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Agreements (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Apprenticeship Indenture (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Assigned Estate of Edward L. Evans - Petition, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Bad Notes (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Baily vs. Baily (Divorce) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bank Protests (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Biddle, Clement Cornell - Biographical Sketch (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Biddle, Dr. John B. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Thomas A. Biddle & Co. (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
  - Bonds (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Brick Yard Rental, 1872 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Calling Cards (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1895-1898 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1906 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Circulars (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Clippings (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Cochran, E.C. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Columbia Manufacturing Company (Box 15, Folder 25-26)
  - Compact Disc (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Contracts for Trees Cut, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Daniel, A.V. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Davis Family Bible Records (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Deeds (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Committee Meeting, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Dewees, Jacob (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Diary of a Trip to Havana and Mexico, 1883 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Envelopes (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Essay (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Evans vs. Owen - Settlement (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Evans vs. Steen, 1875-1877 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Evans Family Register (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Eviction Notice, 1874 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Exercise Book (Geometry), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Exercise Book (Oceanography), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Fabric Swatch (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Fieles, Martin M. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Garden, Andrew - Petition for Relief, 1833 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Good Intent Stage Company (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Greeting Cards (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Guardianship of Children of Ephraim Hughes (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Guardianship of Sarah E. Norton (Box 16, Folder 21-23)
  - John Gwinn & Co. (Box 16, Folder 24-25)
  - Hall & Norwood - Sale to Norwood Bros. (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Hedley, D.B. (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Housekeeper (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Hughes, Ephraim - Medical Examination (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Invitations (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Journal/Harvest Book, 1852-1855 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Journal of a Voyage from Philadelphia to Canton, 1832 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Journal of a Voyage from Canton to Philadelphia, 1833 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Journal of a Voyage from Philadelphia to Canton, 1834 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Journal - Proceedings of the House of Representatives, 18 January - 16 March 1821 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Killough, S., 1857-1860 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Lawrence, Nathaniel (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - List of Articles in Paoli Owned by Joshua Evans, 1841 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - List of Members of Congress - 22nd Congress, 2nd Session (1832-1833) (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - List of Students, 1877 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Literary Debating Society of West Chester Academy - Constitution and Minutes, 1834-1835 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - McFall, Archibald - Petition for Relief, 1803 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Memorandum Book, 1819-1825 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum Book, 1830-1832 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum Book, 1832-1833 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum Book, 1842-1843 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum Book, 1845 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Memorandum Book, 1878-1879 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Memorandum Book ("Miscellanies"), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Mingo Oil Company Stock, 1864-1867 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Money Holder (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Myers, Percival F. - Collector of Tolls (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Neff/Killough Matter, 1858-1864 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Norwood Bros. - Failure, 1886-1888 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Norwood Bros. - License, 1887 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Norwood Bros. - Notes and Accounts (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Norwood & Co. - Monthly Bank Statements, April 1888-April 1890 (Box 18, Folder 8-21)
  - Norwood & Co. - Monthly Bank Statements, June 1890-August 1891 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Norwood & Co. - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Odd Fellows Widows and Orphans Relief Association - Assessments (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Opinions (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Owen, John J., 1889-1892 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Paoli Monument (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Partial Account of Outstanding Debts, 1841-1843 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Patent Rights (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Pearce, Edward Jr. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad Company - Damages to John D. Evans Property, 1876-1880 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Personal Liabilities of Joshua Evans (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Petition to Canal Board, 1854 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Petition to Pennsylvania General Assembly, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Petitions for Tavern Licenses, 1816-1818 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Photographs (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Planets and Seasons - Memorandum Book (In German) (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Poetry (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Post Office Appointment, 1868 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Post Office Department (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Potts, George (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Powers of Attorney (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Promissory Notes, 1805, 1815-1819 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Promissory Notes, 1820, 1829 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Promissory Notes, 1830-1839 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Promissory Notes, 1841-1846 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Promissory Notes, 1855, 1866-1869 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Promissory Notes, 1870-1872, 1876 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Promissory Notes, 1880-1888 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Promissory Notes, 1890-1898 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Promissory Notes, 1900, 1905-1906 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Prospectus - The Times and Constitutional Press (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Reduction of Railroad Fare (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Register of the Officers and Cadets of the U.S. Military Academy, 1832 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Registered Letter Bills, 1868-1869 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Rental Property (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Report Card - South Boston Female Institute, 1896 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Report Cards - Hampden-Sidney College, 1906-1907 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Resolutions (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Resolutions of a Political Meeting Held at Paoli, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Return Registered Letter Receipts (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - South Boston Female Institute - Commencement Program, 1897 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Speeches/Letters to the Editor (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - State Female Normal School - Commencement Program and Certificate, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Stock Certificates - Little Conostogoa Turnpike Road, 1811 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Stock Certificates - Roseland Iron and Coal Company, 1889 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Supplee Steam Engine Company (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Survey Field Book, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Surveys (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Tavern Licenses, 1814-1851 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1841 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1847 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1854 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1871 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1876 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1878-1879 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1888 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1889 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1890 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1896 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1903 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Telephone Contracts, 1887-1888 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Title Abstracts (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Tombstone Inscription - Joshua Evans (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Travel Diaries, 1825-1829 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Tredyffrin School Board (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Tucker, J.D. (Trustee - Norwood Bros.) (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Uderzook, Henry (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Union Protective Association of Berwyn (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Union Ticket - List of Candidates (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Unpaid Letters (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Watson vs. Watson (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Weather Log and List of Members of the Literary Debating Society of West Chester Academy, 1834-1835, 1838 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Whitesides, Peter (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Will of George King (Draft) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Wine Price List (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Wisner, Jacob (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Wrappers (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - One Hundredth Anniversary of the Paoli Massacre (1877) (Box 21, Folder n/a)
  - Rudiments of English Grammar (1812) (Box 21, Folder n/a)
  - The New Testament (Box 21, Folder n/a)
- Series V. Oversized Items (Box Box 22-24)
  There are a large number of oversized items similiar to those contained in the subject files.
  Alphabetical by Subject.
  - Thomas A. Biddle & Co. - Statements of Account (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Bonds (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Certificate (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Construction of Pumping Station at Paoli (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Deeds (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Ann Crow (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Estate of James Davis (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Frederick Landis (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Genealogical Charts (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Insurance Policies (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Maps and Plats (Box 23, Folder n/a)
  - Militia Commission (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers (Encapsulated) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Phrenological Analysis - Edward F. Evans, 1837 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Post Office Department - Accounts Current (Box 24, Folder 6-8)
  - Postmaster Appointments (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Promissory Note (Box 24, Folder 10)